Finding aid for the Edward Nicholas and Dollie Ann Cole papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Edward Nicholas Cole, 1829-1997
  - Personal Materials, 1829-1997
    - Audio/Visual Recordings
      - Fishing, undated; 1 film reels (Box 20)
      - Cole, Carribean, undated; 1 film reels (Box 20)
      - La Pointe Rivier Trip, 1957; 1 film reels (Box 20)
      - Quebec, Canada Trip, 1955; 1 film reels (Box 16)
      - Hunting, 1950; 1 film reels (Box 16)
      - Family, Bloomfield Hills & Northern Michigan, 1966; 1 film reels (Box 16)
      - Cole Retirement, GM Photo., 1974; 1 film reels (Box 16)
      - Film of Family and Friends, 1960; 1 film reels (Box 16)
      - News Coverage of Passing, 1977; 1 film reels (Box 16)
      - Fishing (Master), undated; 1 film reels (Box 16)
      - Bay De Noc and Michigan State Ferry, 1957; 1 film reels (Box 16)
      - Mistassini Lake, 1955; 1 film reels (Box 16)
    - Papers
      - Automobile Hall of Fame Invitation, 1978 (Box 10)
      - Automotive Organization Team (Automotive Old Timers), 1967-1973 (Box 10)
      - Board of Trustees: Development of the Handicapped Inc, 1973 (Box 10)
      - Boy Scouts of America, 1963 (Box 10)
      - Boy Scouts of America: Annual Meeting, 1966 (Box 10)
      - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1964-1974 (Box 18)
      - Christmas Cards, 1973 (Box 10)
      - Clippings (Photocopies), 1997 (Box 10)
      - Detroit Club, 1961-1974 (Box 10)
      - Flight School Notebook, 1975 (Box 10)
      - Georgia Shooting Vacation, 1971 (Box 10)
      - Genealogy: Family Correspondence (Box 10)
      - Genealogy: Family Tree and History (Box 10)
      - Honorary Degrees and Awards, undated (Box 10)
      - Invitations to Serve on Boards, 1974 (Box 10)
      - Memorial, 1977 (Box 10)
      - Memorial Articles, 1977 (Box 10)
      - Pi Kappa Alpha Alumni Magazine, 1967 (Box 10)
      - Resume, 1977 (Box 10)
      - Short Wave Radio Permit, 1975 (Box 10)
      - Misc Papers, 1965-1977 (Box 10)
      - Ferris State University: Honorary Degree, Doctor of Laws, 1973 (Box 14)
      - Widner College: Honorary Degree, Doctor of Engineering, 1969 (Box 14)
      - Misc Awards and Honors (Box 14)
      - Boys Day Scrapbook (Box 19)
    - Photographic Materials
      - Signed Group Photograph, undated (Box 10)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 10)
      - Large Photographs (Box 14)
      - Father of the Year Photo Album, 1963 (Box 15)
      - General Motors Retirement Photo Album, 1974 (Box 15)
      - Memorial Album, 1977 (Box 15)
      - Slide Collection, 1946-1961 (Box 21)
- Dollie Ann Cole, 1968-2016
  The Dollie Ann Cole series contains the correspondence and personal papers of the Michigan and Texas based socialite and philanthropist. The series has been divided into two subseries:
  The Correspondence subseries (0.5 linear feet) contains both personal correspondence and correspondence related to Cole's charity work and media appearances. Materials include a series of condolence letters she received following the passing of Ed Cole in 1977.
  The Papers subseries (1.5 linear feet) includes papers, clippings, photographs,and scrapbooks. The materials highlight Cole's work with national groups such as the Public Broadcasting Service as well as her local charity efforts with groups like the Michigan Humane Society. The subseries also contains papers related to Cole's work with the Saturday Evening Post, including a copy of an opinion column she penned on Cesar Chevaz. The collection also includes a copy of the remembrance article written by Cole's daughter, Ann Cole Pierce, in the Texas-based society magazine, "The Society Diaries".
  - Correspondence, 1968-1976
    - Personal Correspondence
      - 1968-1970 (Box 11)
      - 1971 (Box 11)
      - 1973 (Box 11)
    - Letters of Condolence (Box 11)
    - Correspondence and Clippings, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Misc Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 11)
  - Topical files, 1968-2016
    - American Textile Manufacturers, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Interview: Big 4 Automobile Executives, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Charity and Advocacy Materials, 1970-1977 (Box 11)
    - Checker Motor Group, 1977-1979 (Box 11)
    - Detroit Zoo Commission, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Easter Seals Society Telethon, 1974 (Box 11)
    - European Trip Itinerary, 1969 (Box 11)
    - "An Evening with Sergio Franchi and Friends", 1973 (Box 11)
    - Fashion Shows, undated (Box 11)
    - George Wallace Article, 1975 (Box 11)
    - International Institute, undated (Box 11)
    - Jack Parr Show, 1973 (Box 11)
    - King of Saudi Arabia's Car, 1971 (Box 12)
    - Mark Withers House, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Marty Meehan Fund for Brian DuJardin, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Malatchie Farms, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Media Appearances, 1974-1976 (Box 12)
    - Memorial in "The Society Diaries" Magazine, 2016 (Box 12)
    - Michigan Department of Education-Vocational Rehabilitation, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Michigan Humane Society, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Michigan Cancer Foundation, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Missouri Valley College Commencement Speech, 1973 (Box 12)
    - National Cystic Fibrosis Research Foundation, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Project Hope, 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - Public Broadcasting Service, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - Saturday Evening Post, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - Saturday Evening Post: Caesar Chavez article, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Trip Itineraries, undated (Box 12)
    - Walmart, 1986 (Box 12)
    - White House Event Program, 1970 (Box 12)
    - Women in Business Seminar, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Misc Papers, 1975-1987 (Box 12)
    - Scrapbook Pages, undated (Box 12)
    - "Not for Women Only", 1973; 1 videocassettes (U-Matic) (Box 13)
      (Videocassette)
    - Dollie Cole Photographs, undated (Box 14)